<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jayesh Nair</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jayesh Nair</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Audio Transcription Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/yatt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/yatt/</guid>
      <description>Working on learning about ASR and shipping something cool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reader - Text To Speech Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/read-aloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/read-aloud/</guid>
      <description>Pocket is dead, and speechify costs money. A project to explore if we can run TTS models locally on a phone, and create a great reading experience.&#xA;Track notes and status starting here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Geo-Location data using Deck.gl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/geo-spatial-data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/geo-spatial-data-viz/</guid>
      <description>As an official submission to VGI-Hackathon 2024, created a tool to visualize spatio-temporal geo-location trip data of VGI-Flexi trips.&#xA;GitHub Repo&#xA;Note: The code hasn&amp;rsquo;t been cleaned up after the hackathon. :/&#xA;Stack used:&#xA;Deck.gl (pydeck) - Interactive maps Streamlit - Frontend for the app here&#39;s a quick demo of the platform </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensor data fusion: Camera &amp; Radar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/sensor-fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/sensor-fusion/</guid>
      <description>This was a team project done under supervision of Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt. The goal was to perform late-fusion on radar &amp;amp; camerea detections.&#xA;This was really fun to work on - got to learn about nitty-gritties of model training, evaluation and spatial fusion of detections. I would like to highlight a few sections here from the project.&#xA;Github Repo&#xA;Image Augmentation: Primary problem when it comes to working on road user data is high levels of data imbalance among different classes, we were working with 6 road user classes with the following distribution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/exploring-rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/exploring-rl/</guid>
      <description>This was initially a project done as part of Principles of Autonomy and Decision Making at Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt. The goal was to implement and test Q-Learning and Deep-Q-Learning in a custom environment.&#xA;Currently, this page serves as a gateway to exploring different RL algorithms on various environments, starting with Value function based methods.&#xA;1/ Q-Learning and Deep Q-Learning 1.1/ The Environment: The custom environment was built on top of frameworks such as Gymnasium and PyGames.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
