<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jayesh Nair</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jayesh Nair</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Logs &#39;26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/logs26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/logs26/</guid>
      <description>Jan 1 &amp;lsquo;26. Happy New Year! My last log was posted in October. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the intellectual growth compared to the year 2024. That being said, there are a few things that I was happy about.&#xA;Firstly, this website itself. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a website, or some place to host writings in the past, but this was the first time I felt like calling something &amp;ldquo;a home on the internet&amp;rdquo; (yes, it sounds cheeky).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Websites I frequent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/websites/</guid>
      <description>James Somers Christopher Olah (esp. Neural Networks, Manifolds, and Topology, Understanding Convolutions ) Gwern Branwen Bartosz Ciechanowski (esp. Camera and Lenses, Sound) Distill Jack Schaedler (esp. Seeing Circles, Sines and Signals ) Michael Nielson (esp. Neural Networks and Deep Learning ) Eli Bendersky (esp. How I went about learning Rust, Asimov, programming and the meta ladder) Intellectual Mathematics Fabian Giesen (esp. Linear Algebra toolbox series, Smart) Andrej Karpathy (alt. Bearblog ) Trevor Blackwell (esp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring SAM2 and Scene Graphs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/exploring-scene-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/exploring-scene-graphs/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across an idea, in which scene-graphs are used to describe what is happening in a given video frame, below is a very short demonstration along with a link to colab notebook where I explore using Meta&amp;rsquo;s Segment Anything 2 (SAM2) model to create scene graphs.&#xA;The video we are going to be using is as follows, we want SAM2 to track the cup that contains the ball and in the end tell us the correct position.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logs &#39;25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/logs25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/logs25/</guid>
      <description>Oct 25 &amp;lsquo;25. Been reading the series Exiting Modernity by Meta-Nomad.&#xA;Oct 14 &amp;lsquo;25. Read a decent write up on Alec Radford. For anyone who know&amp;rsquo;s the field, the man is a prolific researcher. His work spans Audio (Generative Audio), Speech (Whisper) , Text (GPT1, GPT2) to Vision (CLIP).&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m still not up to do much work today. So, I have instead been watching a series of videos on the Secret History by the Predictive History YouTube channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audio Transcription Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/yatt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/yatt/</guid>
      <description>Working on learning about ASR and shipping something cool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reader - Text To Speech Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/read-aloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/read-aloud/</guid>
      <description>Pocket is dead, and speechify costs money. A project to explore if we can run TTS models locally on a phone, and create a great reading experience.&#xA;Track notes and status starting here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Geo-Location data using Deck.gl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/geo-spatial-data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/geo-spatial-data-viz/</guid>
      <description>As an official submission to VGI-Hackathon 2024, created a tool to visualize spatio-temporal geo-location trip data of VGI-Flexi trips.&#xA;GitHub Repo&#xA;Note: The code hasn&amp;rsquo;t been cleaned up after the hackathon. :/&#xA;Stack used:&#xA;Deck.gl (pydeck) - Interactive maps Streamlit - Frontend for the app here&#39;s a quick demo of the platform </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recurring Ideas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/2024-7-10-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/2024-7-10-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Ideas I often find repeating to myself.&#xA;The point of wealth is to enable yourself to pursue things for their own sake, but ironically, most times the greatest wealth comes to people who pursue things for their own sake to begin with.&#xA;Struggle is entirely pointless, a distraction, a time sink, a thing that hinders a person to get to a place. No matter how proud you are of your version of the rags to riches, the ill person to healthy, the addict to sober, they are time sinks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensor data fusion: Camera &amp; Radar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/sensor-fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/sensor-fusion/</guid>
      <description>This was a team project done under supervision of Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt. The goal was to perform late-fusion on radar &amp;amp; camerea detections.&#xA;This was really fun to work on - got to learn about nitty-gritties of model training, evaluation and spatial fusion of detections. I would like to highlight a few sections here from the project.&#xA;Github Repo&#xA;Image Augmentation: Primary problem when it comes to working on road user data is high levels of data imbalance among different classes, we were working with 6 road user classes with the following distribution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/exploring-rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/exploring-rl/</guid>
      <description>This was initially a project done as part of Principles of Autonomy and Decision Making at Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt. The goal was to implement and test Q-Learning and Deep-Q-Learning in a custom environment.&#xA;Currently, this page serves as a gateway to exploring different RL algorithms on various environments, starting with Value function based methods.&#xA;1/ Q-Learning and Deep Q-Learning 1.1/ The Environment: The custom environment was built on top of frameworks such as Gymnasium and PyGames.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Hacking: A reading List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/2024-5-6-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/2024-5-6-hack/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to the authors for publishing on the Internet!&#xA;from ESR&amp;rsquo;s Jargon File:&#xA;hacker: n. A person who enjoys exploring the details of programmable systems and how to stretch their capabilities, as opposed to most users, who prefer to learn only the minimum necessary. RFC1392, the Internet Users&amp;rsquo; Glossary, usefully amplifies this as: A person who delights in having an intimate understanding of the internal workings of a system, computers and computer networks in particular.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to work on?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/2023-6-9-decisions-on-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/2023-6-9-decisions-on-work/</guid>
      <description>Update:&#xA;What to work on? What to learn and how to think about this question of spending majority of your time into something? I have been trying to figure out answers to questions as well, and it&amp;rsquo;s not straight-forward.&#xA;I feel our culture / written works around these questions, have a lot of different opinions, and mostly leave out the messy part - the empty dread of not knowing what comes next when you decide upon something.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sounds Of Silence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/2022-3-12-sounds-of-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/2022-3-12-sounds-of-silence/</guid>
      <description>I. “What does silence sound like?” That is not the question I began my day with. I woke up with a cool breeze hitting my body, it is a summer morning - at the backdrop of a warm atmosphere, the fan was running at full speed.&#xA;I checked the time - it was 6:45 AM. it was a pleasant surprise, I slept at 12:00 AM and half expecting myself to wake up early, I had an alarm for 7:15 AM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Ode to the Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/2022-1-30-the_internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/2022-1-30-the_internet/</guid>
      <description>I. On August 15, 1995, Indians woke up to the tariff plan of a new sort of communication service. They could buy dial-up internet.&#xA;At Rs 15,000 a year, it was not quite something the average Indian could afford then.&#xA;I was still a young kid when I had a glimpse of the Internet1. The old dial-up connection tones, the slow speeds and hefty charges levied. But I was part of the generation that grew up with it’s evolving use cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a full-time student pursuing Masters in AI &amp;amp; Autonomous Systems at Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt. Previously I used to work as a Solution&amp;rsquo;s Engineer at Minto.ai and had earned a bachelors in Mechanical Engineering from Pune, India.&#xA;I have a deep interest in making computer&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; things, along with the &amp;ldquo;tools&amp;rdquo; that make them see such as traditional camera&amp;rsquo;s, event based camera&amp;rsquo;s, light-field systems etc. I am constantly on the lookout for opportunities to work on the same.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/excerpts/excerpts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/excerpts/excerpts/</guid>
      <description>Bookmarks for passages / excerpts I come across that resonate with me, for whatever reason.&#xA;I go where they never can&#xA;I float, I don&amp;rsquo;t ever land&#xA;When it&amp;rsquo;s dark, you don&amp;rsquo;t know&#xA;where you goin&amp;rsquo;&#xA;Need a light-bearer to lead you home.&#xA;Preacher Man RAD has a small staff of really smart programmers that can code, write documentation, and provide great technical support. Unlike most companies, we want our smart people working on documentation and supporting our customers - that&amp;rsquo;s the way our products get better!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
