<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Jayesh Nair</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Jayesh Nair</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Logs &#39;26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/logs26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/logs26/</guid>
      <description>Jan 1 &amp;lsquo;26. Happy New Year! My last log was posted in October. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the intellectual growth compared to the year 2024. That being said, there are a few things that I was happy about.&#xA;Firstly, this website itself. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a website, or some place to host writings in the past, but this was the first time I felt like calling something &amp;ldquo;a home on the internet&amp;rdquo; (yes, it sounds cheeky).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logs &#39;25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/logs25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/logs25/</guid>
      <description>Oct 25 &amp;lsquo;25. Been reading the series Exiting Modernity by Meta-Nomad.&#xA;Oct 14 &amp;lsquo;25. Read a decent write up on Alec Radford. For anyone who know&amp;rsquo;s the field, the man is a prolific researcher. His work spans Audio (Generative Audio), Speech (Whisper) , Text (GPT1, GPT2) to Vision (CLIP).&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m still not up to do much work today. So, I have instead been watching a series of videos on the Secret History by the Predictive History YouTube channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sounds Of Silence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/2022-3-12-sounds-of-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/2022-3-12-sounds-of-silence/</guid>
      <description>I. “What does silence sound like?” That is not the question I began my day with. I woke up with a cool breeze hitting my body, it is a summer morning - at the backdrop of a warm atmosphere, the fan was running at full speed.&#xA;I checked the time - it was 6:45 AM. it was a pleasant surprise, I slept at 12:00 AM and half expecting myself to wake up early, I had an alarm for 7:15 AM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Ode to the Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/2022-1-30-the_internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/2022-1-30-the_internet/</guid>
      <description>I. On August 15, 1995, Indians woke up to the tariff plan of a new sort of communication service. They could buy dial-up internet.&#xA;At Rs 15,000 a year, it was not quite something the average Indian could afford then.&#xA;I was still a young kid when I had a glimpse of the Internet1. The old dial-up connection tones, the slow speeds and hefty charges levied. But I was part of the generation that grew up with it’s evolving use cases.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
